

# Nick Baughman

Fullstack Software Engineer	
	405 Sterling Place, Floor 1, Brooklyn, New York, US, NY 11238
	(225)247-4814
	nbaugh1@gmail.com
	http://nickbaughman.com
	☐ English
BACKGROUND	
	ABOUT
	Self motivated full-stack developer with a background in customer service pursuing a path in software development. Experienced in developing full stack applications using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React/Redux. I bring a wide range of skills and attention to detail that have helped high end restaurants develop world class beverage programs with reputations for exceptional service. I am a multi-faceted person passionate in many areas of interest including philosophy, photography, drawing, and computer hardware.
	WORK EXPERIENCE
	Software Engineer Intern, 1DNE Jan, 2020 - Jan, 2020 □ 1 day
	Software Engineer Student, Flatiron School  Jan, 2019 - Jan, 2019

Oriented Programming, Model View Controller design pattern, RESTful routing, clean coding habits, building ar

interacting with private and public APIs and more.

- Project 1
  Project 2
  Project 3
  Project 4
  Project 5
- Bartender, Union Square Hospitality Group

Jan, 2019 - Jan, 2020 □ 1 year

#### Summary of Manhatta

- o
  - Brought in to aid in development and refinement of beverage program at Manhatta restaurant
- o
  - Excelled at multitasking in fast paced environment handling responsibilities including building cocktails to guests' desired specifications, delegating tasks to team members, and tracking orders and inventory
- o
  - Organized and streamlined systems resulting in increased efficiency leading to regularly exceed sales projections, trained and educated bar and dining room teams, recruited talented new members to bar team

### □ SKILLS

#### **Frontend Development**

HTML CSS Javascript React Redux Gatsby

#### **Backend Development**

Ruby on Rails API REST MVC PostgreSQL GraphQL

#### **Fullstack Development**

Ruby Javascript API OOP Sinatra MVC JAMStack REST Ruby on Rails

## **EDUCATION**

#### Software Engineering, Certificate, Flatiron School

Jan, 2019 - Jan, 2019

#### Political Science, , Louisiana State University

Jan, 2002 - Jan, 2006